number two what is the iup pack name for
the following compound we have another
one here we need to find the longest
carbon chain this is not always going to
be just the chain that is given to you
from left to right we need to make sure
we get the longest one possible and so
this one snakes up over here that is
going to be the longest carbon chain now
we have to number left to right or right
to left and we want the first
substituent occurring soonest so we will
in this case number right to left 1 two
3 four five 6 7 eight because we have a
substituent on three if we numbered left
to right we wouldn't have a substituent
until carbon 4 then we see what
substituents we have we have a methyl
here we have a methyl here and we have
an ethyl there if we want to number
these alphabetically we will do the
ethyl first so we need five ethyl then
we would name the methyls at the same
time because they're the